welcome to yoga and you welcome to 136.1
yoga studio today as an extension of the
balancing posture sequence today we will
be talking about utkat asana
[Music]
utkatasana is
literally translated as the chair pose
here this posture
like any other balancing posture helps
you to improve your concentration helps
you to improve your
kinesthetic sense helps you to improve
your body awareness and this helps you
to tone up your thai
your calf muscle
and this is the traditional way of doing
a nude katasana so what you need to do
here
inhale
raise your heel up raise your arm up to
the shoulder level
turn your palm down with an exhalation
slowly go down squat down halfway this
squat you can decide but make sure the
vertex and the tailbone are in line and
stretch your arm forward don't lean
forward
stay there
with your breathing
and then come up slowly
after five breaths or so
exhale bring your heel down bring your
arm down the key points here is
you have to keep your focus in one point
in front of you make sure the knee is
pointing forward as you're doing the
width and don't spread it to the side
keep it pointing forward
do not lean forward
keep the crown of the head the vertex
and the tailbone in line this is one
variation of it
once you're comfortable with this
then go for the next one raise up to the
full and squat down to the foot
[Music]
once you want to raise up again come on
inhale and up
exhale bring your heel down bring your
arm down slowly
[Music]